How many pieces of real estate or how
many properties do you currently own right now?
We have right around 130 different properties.
Wow, that's amazing. And how long
have you been in real estate for?
13 years.
13 years. So, you know, for
someone who's starting out in 2022,
what is your best piece of advice
to someone pursuing the real estate industry?
The best piece of advice that I have is to
take the risk, but find properties that are below value.
And the leverage that you get with real estate
is unreal. You might put $10,000 down on a property,
but if it's worth $300,000 and it goes
up 10% that year, you just tripled your money.
It's on paper, but think very long term with it.
I met a guy that bought a property
for $11,000 that he got offered for $3 million.
And that was 60 years ago. So the
power of real estate over time, you know,
you're never going to buy a
house and it goes to zero.
That might happen with a stock,
that might happen with a business,
but real estate does not go to zero.
Today, we're going to be spending a day
in the life with Matt Teufke and Alex Kaufman,
who are two owners of a real estate brokerage.
They have over a hundred properties and
nearly 200 agents that work under them.
They're one of the most entrepreneurial
real estate brokerages in all of Texas.
And we can't wait to take you
guys through a day in the life.
Yeah. I mean, I can show you around, man.
Awesome, man.
This is like hangout office. My wife's
actually over here working. This is Lexi.
Nice to meet you.
And we really say like, Hey,
this office is open to everybody.
Right.
So we'll give you the code. You want to
throw an event? You want to throw a party?
Have at it. This is their office.
And how long have you guys had this?
Kind of, I guess, spot right here.
Moved in here August 1st.
Wow. Okay.
So we still got the Round Rock office, but
we moved into this one a couple months ago.
Right.
Feels like we've been here for like six
months, but it was just two months ago.
We don't own it. We
wish we did. We're renting it.
Yeah, we'll show you around. We got two offices upstairs.
We own a first right of refusal to buy it.
Yeah, Alex got the, that's basically
so for anybody who doesn't know,
we get the opportunity to buy
it if he gets any other offers.
Oh, that's sweet.
Yeah.
So this actually used to be
a church, like a Bible study group.
This is a spot where agents can come and work.
This is Chris Sweeney, entrepreneur.
Class is in session, Sweeney.
Yeah. So we leave these offices open. We'll do trainings.
Yeah.
You know, sometimes people close the
door when they're cold calling or something.
We'll check in here.
We'll talk to Elliot.
That's my boy Elliot, cold calling.
Okay. You know, that's my deal.
Training room where we run
classes and trainings and everything.
And then there's just a office for Mr. Jonathan Richards.
He's not in yet.
Big country.
AKA big country.
You all meet him later.
Jonathan does a lot of classes for us.
He actually is big country.
You'll see him and he'll be like, yeah.
That's big country.
I see it on the door.
Every now and then, you know, come
up here and celebrate a little tequila.
Oh, that's sick.
But these are all classes.
We teach classes.
If you look here, there's basically, there is
actually a class every single day this month.
You want to partner with your agents on deals.
It's not just about the commissions.
It's like you want to invest in real estate together.
How is that process kind of work where you start getting commissions, but
then eventually you guys partner together with the people you bring in on deals.
How does that kind of look like that process?
Yeah.
At the end of the day, it's all about fun.
Finding value.
You don't have to go make commissions for
two years and then buy real estate with us.
You can just buy it with us right now.
That is what's so cool, right?
Is that never existed for me and ultimately what we're trying to create running into an opportunity that, you know, I was 24 years old and
I know that there's value in this property and not being able to buy it or take it down because my broker didn't do commercial real estate.
Right, right.
And now looking back.
I could have raised capital.
I could have brought on partners, but you
don't know that stuff when you're just getting started.
So that type of agent can come here and find that opportunity and we'll buy it with them and we'll show them
how to do it and we'll give them equity and then we'll create a new entity and then we'll have 10 properties.
You guys create content, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, we do create.
Do you have like a studio or something like that?
Yeah.
You want to check it out?
Let's do it.
Preach you guys from other brokerages because it sounds like
I love the working with and not for one another.
Yeah.
You know, whereas I feel
like a lot of other people.
The brokerages are a lot more very corporate and very kind of
like cutthroat and strict as far as roles and stuff like that.
Kind of what I guess
separates you apart from other brokerages.
Yeah, there's a lot right
and I love talking about it.
So the logistics side of things on
what we encourage and how we approach things.
It's very different, right?
So most brokerages are like, hey, hey man, get your sales up, you know, get
us more commissions and we go and say, hey, what are you really trying to do?
And how can we support that?
And we're a built-in business partner.
So build your own brand, build your own team,
wholesale, buy real estate, make commissions if you want to.
It's creating generational wealth, but then
utilizing the license as one tool.
Unofficial core value, fucking supportive.
And we've got special person in here.
Her name is Killer.
Is that Killer Kim?
All right.
How you doing?
Say hello.
Hello, everybody.
Good morning.
What are we working on today?
Doing cold calls.
All cold calls.
This morning.
This is my mom and she
is the ultimate of the cold call.
So a question for you
then, and it'll be real quick.
Cold calling primarily has to do with like sales, right?
Correct.
So what is your best piece of advice to someone who's getting into
sales or what is your secret to sales when you're on a cold call?
I just try and be authentic.
You know what I mean?
I don't, I'm just who I am.
I love to talk to people.
I'm just authentic.
I think it's amazing that you
guys like get to work together.
Kind of like a mom and son thing.
Exactly.
Absolutely love that.
She raised my brother and I, single mom, and she owns 16, 17 properties
and worked a full-time job in construction and just did a really great job.
You might hear someone's got 20 properties.
It doesn't mean that they're just making all this money.
They got to keep pushing forward and keep hustling.
You have foundation problems.
You have septic problems.
You have roofing problems.
I mean, there's a lot that goes into that, you
know, and my goal was to pay them all off.
Right.
I have all of them paid off besides three.
Wow.
That's awesome.
I'm very glad.
Maybe she is making 20k a month.
Yeah.
19 to be exact.
We're building up this room right
here, which is kind of cool.
You guys might respect this.
It's not there yet, but the goal is for agents to go in
there and to go live on Instagram, TikTok, Facebook, YouTube at any time.
Just record their own content.
That's awesome.
You going in there?
I'm going to call.
Come on, baby.
Out back is actually the marketing.
So this is, this is one
of our secrets in a sense.
So we got the machine.
That's a big value.
But then marketing, you know, we're constantly thinking, how
can we be different and do things that nobody's doing?
Yeah.
We have a huge focus on this.
The social media side is one of
the most valuable things that we do.
Yeah.
And it's the backbone of a lot
of stuff that happens here at Tiri.
And have you guys kind of like emphasize that to
some of the agents that are part of your business?
Yeah, of course.
We encourage it.
We try to tell people, go be different, right?
Like if you're doing an open house, don't just
film yourself and say, hey, I'm at this open house.
Like make it you.
Yeah.
And it's a bigger mission also.
It lets people feel free in who they are.
Let's show you the marketing team.
Let's do it.
They, these are the people who make everything happen.
How you doing, bro?
Good.
How are you?
Oh, hi.
They're good.
Check it.
Andrew should be the one on film.
He's actually the actor.
No, I'm just behind the camera.
What are you cooking up right here?
So currently editing a video we recorded last week.
It was a pretty big project.
But we want to get our message out, right?
That TRE is the home of the real entrepreneur.
And so we want that message
to be heard around the world.
And so this is like a
shorter, probably 60 to 90 second video.
So now cooking it all up.
What is the importance that you've seen of like
leveraging content for the brand or TRE just in general?
Yeah, it's the most important thing.
I mean, we live in a digital age right now and you know, everything's
online and you're able to be so much more effective through digital marketing, right?
Like instead of going to a class and
teaching last night, we reached 10 people last night.
You put something on social media, you
can read hundreds of thousands, millions of people.
And so putting out digital content is I think
the best way to do marketing in today's age.
You know, this is cool.
I'm going to take over
the camera for a little bit.
I'm just saying.
What's up, guys?
It's Jack here.
I'm his twin now.
But I'm kidding.
I'm Josh.
I've been working the camera today,
but now we're ready to hop in.
Come on.
Welcome, Josh.
This is where a lot of the magic happens.
MTV Crib style.
And we're live, boys.
So this is where we record
our podcast, a lot of our content.
What was like the original inspiration to start the podcast?
Was it really just to get to know people's
story and kind of network or what was it?
The original inspiration?
Just maybe similar to y'all, you know, I have to dive in and I'd love to know more,
but just believing that the only way to scale and to get a message out is through social media.
So,
we just constantly like Andrew saying instead of talking
to 10 people, we'd like to talk to 10 million.
What's your favorite podcast that you've ever done?
Grant.
Grant?
Yeah.
Why?
Because it turned into a business meeting.
So,
it's a good story.
Do you guys remember when Clubhouse was like super popular?
Yeah.
Yes.
So Clubhouse came on, Grant was on it like 2 in the morning
and he was only allowing a certain amount of people to talk to him.
And somebody got up and like, hey,
Grant, I'm really excited to be here.
Would you come on my podcast?
He said, absolutely.
Yeah.
Grantcardone.com.
So I emailed him and I was like, I kind
of, you know, lied in the sense, but not really.
I was like, hey, I heard that you mentioned you'd come on the podcast and he
signed up to do our podcast and he was going to do it for 10, 15 minutes.
Right?
And we knew the night before we're
like, dude, this is like our Super Bowl.
We got Uncle G, right?
And so we quickly like
we like strategize the whole night.
Like how do we approach this meeting?
And we knew that he had certain things that he wanted
to talk about and that he wanted to sell in a sense.
So we just did it for
him in the first five minutes.
Like we're like, you know, your book just came out.
You got your new show.
We just said everything that
he would have wanted to promote.
And then we just start talking about other things.
And in the middle of the podcast, he's
like this turned into a business meeting, huh?
Like, hell yeah, dude.
Yeah.
And so we talked for another 15 minutes.
And just got more out
of it than we were hoping.
We're more than we're hoping, honestly.
But it was just funny because we
had that strategy and it really worked out.
Just shows you that if you're persistent and you
just shoot your shot, doesn't matter who it is.
Yeah.
He might just say, yeah, didn't get creative.
And then man, you know,
everyone thought I knew Uncle G.
So everyone's calling me trying to
get deals in front of Grant.
Like, like two days later, like
I got to talk to Grant.
I'm like, not right now, guys.
I didn't let him know that I didn't really know.
We actually do social media ourselves.
I'm going to go record some TikToks with my boy.
Andrew right now.
Come on.
Hey guys, Matt's actually right in
the middle of doing a podcast.
Let's go get some behind the scenes looks.
How long have you been in real estate for?
For about five years.
Okay.
And what is your best piece of advice
to someone pursuing the real estate industry in 2022?
Learn how to find value and find deals.
Whether you're a real estate agent,
a wholesaler, an investor, you're raising capital.
If you can learn the one skill of how to identify value in anything
that you're looking at and learn how to identify an opportunity and find deals,
then you can go into any
market in any condition and make money.
Wow.
If you had to start from zero and
you had one year to make a million dollars,
and your life depended on it, what would you do?
Wholesale land here in Austin, Texas.
We've wholesaled some land tracks and we've
made a lot of money doing it.
And so I'd go and I'd find some, find a good deal, find some
good land, and I would get it on a contract at a good price.
And then I'd go find a developer or another end buyer
that'd be willing to pay more than I have it at.
And I'd do that once, maybe twice.
And I bet if I spent all my time
doing that, I could make a million dollars easy.
What we're going to do next is
I got to head over to the roundabout.
We're going to go meet with the machine
in our call center, let you all meet Chris.
But before we go, Jonathan Big Country is up there
teaching a skills workshop to some of our coaching agents.
So let's go check in and
show you all behind the scenes there.
So now I have my OCD right here, right?
We have classes like Matt
told you earlier every single day.
That one there specifically is for coaching agents.
These are entrepreneurs who joined, who
don't have a bunch of experience.
They're going to be doing a lot of things.
So he's up there teaching them, I think,
about listing appointments and how to secure a listing.
We're going to go check out
the machine over in Round Rock.
We're going to take a quick little drive.
We've had a full day today, but let's
go meet up with Chris and the machine.
So we just left one
of your guys' offices in Austin.
Where are we at right now?
Right now we're in Round Rock, and
this is where the machine is being built.
I'll take you guys inside.
We'll get to meet Chris.
He's the department head for the machine.
And I'll let him tell you guys what he's
building and what we're doing here at TRE Rock.
We're going to be doing some of the building
and what we're doing here at TRE with the machine.
Chris is on a call.
We'll come back.
So I help run, obviously, the machine.
I'm head of sales here at TyfKey Realty.
I help Alex and gang
basically with all the lead generation.
We do inbound, outbound, all that great kind of stuff.
Basically, in a nutshell, if you're looking to see if
a home has a pool or what the price is,
we reach out to you.
And we walk you through the whole home buying
process from getting an agent, credit repair if needed,
all the way to the financing portion.
We take care of you.
So we keep the money in-house.
We send that client to a trusted partner, a
trusted lending partner, and a trusted credit repair partner.
And we make it a one-of-a-kind experience.
Do you want to check out where the action happens?
Brother, come on, man.
Let's do this.
Yeah, let's do it.
MTV Cribs.
All right.
Thank you.
So this is good timing.
So typically, we do a lot of our white boarding.
We run numbers, processes, quality, all that good stuff.
A little bit of secret sauce
on the board, so watch out.
I'm just kidding.
So we got all that here.
This is our head for the outbound side.
This is Ryan Matthias.
He helps us with all the outbound.
All right, guys.
We just pulled up to
the Tyfkey Real Estate Happy Hour.
We just finished up over at their
call center over at the machine office.
And yeah, Matt and Alex just invited me.
Yeah, Matt and Alex just invited us
over to their happy hour for their brokerage.
So we're just going to be talking
to some agents, maybe enjoying some good food.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
So I got my law degree, and I
practiced law for about 15 years and realized hour-for-hour
work is only going to get you paid
hour-for-hour, and there's 24 hours in a day.
So I decided to move over into
the real estate industry, started a title office.
That's amazing.
And so now I'm here doing this, having fun,
and then my team's at the office making money.
From what you've seen throughout your career,
how can someone do something that they're not
going to do in their career?
How can someone become financially free in today's world?
Sometimes you've got to jump out of a
plane and build the parachute on the way down.
It doesn't matter what horse you're on,
just make sure you're on a horse.
Surround yourself with people who are smarter than you.
If some old dog is offering
their time to you, take it.
I was just talking with Mark.
My 22-year-old was trying to figure out if he
wanted to buy a house or not, and I just
did everything I could to make him buy the house.
You've just got to get started.
Well, guys, that wraps up today's video, Day
in the Life with Matt Tyfkey and Alex
Kaufman, two co-owners of the Tyfkey Real Estate Happy Hour.
We've got to talk to a lot of agents,
brokerage owners, and just learned a lot about real
estate, and I've really enjoyed
spending the day with you guys.
Thank you guys so much for having us.
Yeah, man.
That was a blast, dude.
It was an eventful day, hopefully provided value.
Appreciate you guys.
Having fun at the happy
hour, man, so it was great.
Really fun.
Yeah, bro.
Answered a lot of questions.
Hopefully, that got to bring you guys inside
on what it actually looks like to run the
real estate brokerage, and we appreciate you, guys.
We appreciate you, guys.
Have fun.
Thanks, man.
Let's不知道 what That's gonna be
in real estate, bro.
are all around the country and the world where
can they find you guys right here baby 512-914-4806
512-914-4806 typekeyrealestate.com instagram youtube facebook
we're easy man tick tock be
real now we're easy man reach out let's get
it let's get it hey appreciate you guys again man
seriously hey if you guys enjoyed today's video
make sure you leave us a like subscribe james
from the school of hard knocks we're here with
jack and josh had a blast today hey stay tuned
for more a lot of good
content on the way let's get it